Verle G. Kaiser Papers 1932-1982
Washington State University Libraries: Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
- Correspondence, Series 4
  - Narrative Trip Reports and Technical Correspondence, 1955-1965; 84 items. (Box 7, Folder 518)
  - Narrative Trip Reports and Technical Correspondence, 1955-1965; 51 items. (Box 7, Folder 519)
  - Narrative Trip Reports and Technical Correspondence, 1967-1971; 44 items. (Box 7, Folder 520)
  - On Books, 1960-1980; 80 items. (Box 7, Folder 521)
  - On History of the Pacific Northwest, 1964-1981; 30 items. (Box 7, Folder 522)
  - Organizational Stages, Columbia Plateau Resources Council, 1965; 64 items. (Box 7, Folder 523)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1961-1964; 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 524)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1941-1976; 70 items. (Box 7, Folder 525)
  - Planning Conservation, 1950-1964; 9 items. (Box 7, Folder 526)
  - Reply to Pat Hollister, 1978; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 527)
  - Response by A.J. Webber, State Conservationist, to David J. Doneen, 1966; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 528)
  - Response by Orlo W. Krauter to Doneen, 1966; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 529)
  - Response to Doneen by Dean M. Barney, Idaho State Farm Bureau Federation, 1966; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 530)
  - Response to Doneen by Lee T. Morgan, 1966; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 531)
  - Response to Doneen by Woodrow I. Rasmussen, 1966; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 532)
  - Retired Conservation Officer Fears for Palouse Topsoil, by Hester Pulling. Spokesman Review, 1978; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 533)
  - Technical Material, 1940-1967; 43 items. (Box 7, Folder 534)
  - Trip Reports, Nicaragua, 1966-1968; 24 items. (Box 7, Folder 535)
  - Trip Reports, Nicaragua, 1966-1971; 34 items. (Box 7, Folder 536)
  - Trip Reports, Nicaragua, 1968-1970; 52 items. (Box 7, Folder 537)
  - Trip Reports, Nicaragua, 1947-1952; 47 items. (Box 7, Folder 538)
  - Verle G. Kaiser: Concerns as District Conservationist, Colfax, Washington, 1953-1955; 52 items. (Box 7, Folder 539)
  - Verle G. Kaiser: Concerns as District Conservationist, Colfax, Washington, 1945-1947; 63 items. (Box 7, Folder 540)
- Erosion, Series 5
  - "A Critical Look at the Soil Erosion Problems of the Palouse", 1978; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 541)
    - Script for Slide Presentation, 1978; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 542)
    - Update, 1978; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 543)
  - Adams County, Erosion Damage, 1951-1952; 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 544)
  - After Effects on Crop, 1942-1957; 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 545)
  - An Informal Report, Run-Off Erosion Damage, Whitman County, 1945-1946; 10 items. (Box 7, Folder 546)
  - ARS Workshop, Pacific Northwest, 1977; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 547)
  - CCC: its Erosion Control Work in the Inland Empire, undated; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 548)
  - Comparison of Precipitation, Soil Erosion, and Wheat Yields, Whitman County, 1933-1975; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 549)
  - Computer Program for Land Treatment in The Palouse, 1976; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 550)
  - Crop Yields Lowered by Erosion, 1949; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 551)
  - Damage to Oregon Farms and Ranches by the 1964 Floods, 1965; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 552)
  - Description of Different Methods of Measuring Soil Losses by Erosion: The Altutin Method, undated; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 553)
  - "Dikes to Stop Erosion," Wenatchee Daily World, 1970; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 554)
  - "Early Seeding of Winter Wheat for Erosion Control," Luke J. Best, 1958; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 555)
  - Effect of Cropping Systems on Erosion Control, North Idaho and Eastern Washington, 1967; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 556)
  - Effect of Cropping Systems on Erosion Control, North Idaho and Eastern Washington, 1967; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 557)
  - Effect of Cropping Systems on Erosion Control, North Idaho and Eastern Washington, 1968; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 558)
  - Effect of Cropping and Tillage Methodson Dry Aggregate Soil Structure, 1963; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 559)
  - Effect of Different Cropping Systems on Moisture Conservation in the Latah-Rock Creek Area, 1968; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 560)
  - Effect of Terracing on Soil Losses, Guthriem Oklahoma, Tyler, Texas, La Crosse, Wisconsin, Bethany, Montana, and Pullman, Washington, undated; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 561)
  - Erosion and Flood Stories, 1965; 5 items. (Box 7, Folder 562)
  - Erosion Control and Runoff Disposal Practices in Southeastern Idaho's Dry Cropland Area, 1966-1968; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 563)
  - Erosion Damage, Adams County, 1952-1955; 17 items. (Box 7, Folder 564)
  - Erosion Damage, Pacific Northwest Grasslands, 1965; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 565)
  - Erosion Damage, Whitman County Farmlands, 1964-1965; 5 items. (Box 7, Folder 566)
  - Erosion Damage, Whitman County Farmlands, 1965-1966; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 567)
  - Erosion Damage, Whitman County Farmlands, 1966-1967; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 568)
  - Erosion Damage, Whitman County Farmlands, 1969-1970; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 569)
  - Erosion of Topsoil Reduces Productivity, J.H. Stallings, 1950; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 570)
  - Erosion Problems of the Palouse, 1976; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 571)
  - Erosion Problems of the Palouse, 1976; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 572)
  - Erosion Problems of the Palouse, 1977; 5 items. (Box 7, Folder 573)
  - Farm Planning, Erosion Control, Othello, 1952; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 574)
  - Ferry, Grant, Adams and Lincoln Counties, 1981-1982; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 575)
  - Field Tour and Conference on Wind Erosion, 1969; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 576)
  - Floods of December: Far Western States, 1964; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 577)
  - General File, 1977-1980; 12 items. (Box 7, Folder 578)
  - Generalized Water Erosion Map, Columbia Plateau of Idaho, Oregon, and Washington, 1967; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 579)
  - Generalized Water Erosion Map, Columbia Plateau of Idaho, Oregon, and Washington, 1967; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 580)
  - Gully Erosion, 1934; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 581)
  - "Help Me," by George Harten, Soil Scientist, Colfax, undated; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 582)
  - Hydrolic Data: Outside the Palouse. Flood Damage as a Form of Erosion, 1949; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 583)
  - Hydrolic Data: Outside the Palouse. Flood Damage as a Form of Erosion, 1963-1965; 17 items. (Box 8, Folder 584)
  - Hydrolic Data: Outside the Palouse. Flood Damage as a Form of Erosion, 1946, 1954-1970; 13 items. (Box 8, Folder 585)
  - Idaho-Washington Resource Conservation and Development Project, 1964; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 586)
  - Kudzu-Erosion Control in the Southeast, 1939; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 587)
  - Legends Used In Erosion Damage Surveys, 1940, 1968, and 1978; 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 588)
  - Map and Materials Showing the Rate of Soil Destruction by Water Erosion in Columbia Plateau Area, 1967; 6 items. (Box 8, Folder 589)
  - Meeting On Erosion and Sedimentation Flood Season, 1964-1965; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 590)
  - Miscellaneous Material on Erosion, 1950-1966; 8 items. (Box 8, Folder 591)
  - Missouri Flat Creek: Erosion Damage, 1975-1976; 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 592)
    - Surveys, 1976-1977; 5 items. (Box 8, Folder 593)
    - Surveys, 1977-1978; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 594)
    - Surveys, 1977-1979; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 595)
    - Surveys, 1979-1980; 7 items. (Box 8, Folder 596)
  - The Movement of Water and Subsequent Soil Erosion, 1977; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 597)
  - The Movement of Water and Subsequent Soil Erosion, 1978; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 598)
  - Pacific Northwest, 1939-1965; 5 items. (Box 8, Folder 599)
  - Pacific Northwest Erosion Damage, Spring 1965; 21 items. (Box 8, Folder 600)
  - Palouse:
    - undated, 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 601)
    - Erosion Damage Reports, 1977-1978; 27 items. (Box 8, Folder 602)
    - Erosion Data, Crop Yield Research Information, 1978-1980; 9 items. (Box 8, Folder 603)
    - Erosion Talk, 1977-1978; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 604)
    - Land Reshaping, 1959-1966; 7 items. (Box 8, Folder 605)
    - "Palouse Program" Outline, Spokane County Conservation District, 1981; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 606)
    - Palouse River Basin Erosion Damage, 1977-1978; 20 items. (Box 8, Folder 607)
    - Palouse River Basin Erosion Damage, Erosion Data, 1976-1977; 6 items. (Box 8, Folder 608)
    - Technical Materials on Soil Erosion and Control Methods, undated; 5 items. (Box 8, Folder 609)
  - Plan for Erosion Control: Colville AC and W Base, 1952; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 610)
  - Pleasant Valley Watershed, 1980; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 611)
  - Preliminary Report of Erosion Damage to Farmlands in Whitman County, 1945-1946; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 612)
  - Preliminary Reports, Stubble Mulch Trials, 1946; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 613)
  - Principles of Water Erosion, 1940-1950; 5 items. (Box 8, Folder 614)
  - Principles of Water Erosion, 1953-1980; 11 items. (Box 8, Folder 615)
  - Rainfall, Erosion Losses from Cropland East of the Rocky Mountains, 1965; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 616)
  - Reports from Erosion Control Demonstration Project, Dayton, Washington, 1940-1942; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 617)
  - Report of Effectiveness of Conservation Practices with Soil Loss Summary, 1940; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 618)
  - Report of Erosion Damage, Whitman County, 1965-1966; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 619)
  - Sedimentation, 1963; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 620)
  - Sedimentation, 1963-1975; 23 items. (Box 8, Folder 621)
  - Sedimentation. Problems of Washington, 1973; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 622)
  - Soil Erosion and Farming Practices that Aid Such Erosion, 1978; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 623)
  - Soil Erosion and Water Pollution in the Inland Empire, 1967; 9 items. (Box 8, Folder 624)
  - Soil Erosion, 1967; 5 items. (Box 8, Folder 625)
  - Soil Erosion News Stories and Articles, 1965; 17 items. (Box 8, Folder 626)
  - Soil Loss on Fields with Diversion Ditches on Farms in Dayton, Washington, 1940; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 627)
  - Soil Removal Through Water and Water Pollution, 1977; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 628)
  - Soil Slips, 1944-1945; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 629)
  - Special Fields to Watch, 1947; 7 items. (Box 9, Folder 630)
  - Spokane Water Quality Committee Management Practices, 1978-1979; 17 items. (Box 9, Folder 631)
  - Stubble Mulch and the Cheatgrass Problem in Pacific Northwest grasslands, 1963; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 632)
  - Summary of Data from the Runoff Studies near Dayton, Washington, 1939-1942; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 633)
  - Those December Rains, 1965; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 634)
  - Tillage Erosion, 1967; 24 items. (Box 9, Folder 635)
  - To Control Water Erosion, Runoff and Sedimentation on the Grasslands of the Columbia Plateau, 1968; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 636)
  - To Control Water Erosion, Runoff and Sedimentation on the Grasslands of the Columbia Plateau, 1968; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 637)
  - USDA Reconnaisance Report on Erosion, Sedimentation and Related Land Resources: Portneuf River Basin, Idaho, 1965; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 638)
  - USDA SCS Annual Report, 1934-1935; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 639)
  - "Waffling Streambanks Against Erosion", 1965; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 640)
  - Water Erosion Under Irrigation, undated; 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 641)
  - Wind Erosion
    - 1955-1972, 32 items. (Box 9, Folder 642)
    - 1971, 7 items. (Box 9, Folder 643)
    - Control Guide, 1975; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 644)
    - Mechanics and Control, undated; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 645)
    - State of Washington, 1971; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 646)
    - Walla Walla County, Washington, 1967; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 647)
  - Whitman County Composite, undated; 19 items. (Box 9, Folder 648)
  - Whitman County Erosion Caused by the Use of Summerfallow: Whitman Co. Water Quality Comm., 1975; 4 items. (Box 9, Folder 649)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1939-1940; 9 items. (Box 9, Folder 650)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1941-1942; 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 651)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1942-1943; 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 652)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1943-1945; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 653)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1945-1946; 10 items. (Box 9, Folder 654)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1946-1947; 4 items. (Box 9, Folder 655)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1947-1948; 9 items. (Box 9, Folder 656)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1948-1949; 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 657)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1949-1950; 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 658)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1950-1951; 7 items. (Box 9, Folder 659)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1951-1952; 13 items. (Box 9, Folder 660)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1952-1953; 29 items. (Box 9, Folder 661)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1953-1954; 17 items. (Box 9, Folder 662)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1954-1955; 17 items. (Box 9, Folder 663)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1955-1956; 7 items. (Box 9, Folder 664)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1956-1957; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 665)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1957-1958; 45 items. (Box 9, Folder 666)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1958-1959; 25 items. (Box 9, Folder 667)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1959-1960; 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 668)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1960-1961; 17 items. (Box 9, Folder 669)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1961-1962; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 670)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1962-1963; 4 items. (Box 9, Folder 671)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1963; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 672)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1962-1963; 11 items. (Box 9, Folder 673)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1962-1963; 18 items. (Box 9, Folder 674)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1963-1964; 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 675)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1964-1965; 8 items. (Box 9, Folder 676)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1966-1967; 4 items. (Box 9, Folder 677)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1967-1968; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 678)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1967-1968; 10 items. (Box 9, Folder 679)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1968-1969; 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 680)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1969-1970; 10 items. (Box 9, Folder 681)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1970-1971; 15 items. (Box 9, Folder 682)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1971-1972; 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 683)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1972-1973; 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 684)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1973-1974; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 685)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1974-1975; 12 items. (Box 10, Folder 686)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1975-1976; 7 items. (Box 10, Folder 687)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1976-1977; 14 items. (Box 10, Folder 688)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1977-1978; 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 689)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1978-1979; 18 items. (Box 10, Folder 690)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1979-1980; 15 items. (Box 10, Folder 691)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1980-1981; 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 692)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1982; 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 693)
  - Whitman County Erosion Damage, 1982; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 694)
  - Whitman County: Special Fields, 1940-1982; 4 items. (Box 10, Folder 695)
  - Whitman County: Special Fields, 1980; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 696)
  - Whitman County: Palouse Erosion Control Project, 1979; 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 697)
  - Whitman County: Report on Erosion Damage, 1977-1978; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 698)
- Field Diaries, Series 6
  - Index to Kaiser Diaries, undated; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 699)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1934-1936; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 700)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1935; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 701)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1937; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 702)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1937-1938; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 703)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1938-1939; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 704)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1938-1942; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 705)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1939-1940; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 706)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1940-1941; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 707)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1941; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 708)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1942-1943; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 709)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1943-1944; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 710)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1944-1945; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 711)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1945-1946; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 712)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1945-1948; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 713)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1946-1948; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 714)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1948-1950; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 715)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1950; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 716)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1951-1952; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 717)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1952-1954; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 718)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1952-1957; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 719)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1954-1955; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 720)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1956-1958; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 721)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 722)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1959; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 723)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1960; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 724)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1961; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 725)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1962; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 726)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1963-1964; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 727)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1964-1965; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 728)
  - Agronomy Field Diary. Also "Register of Groups", 1966; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 729)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1966; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 730)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1963-1967; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 731)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1967; 5 items. (Box 11, Folder 732)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1968-1969; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 733)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1968-1969; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 734)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1970; 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 735)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1972-1975; 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 736)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1975-1976; 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 737)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1975-1976; 6 items. (Box 12, Folder 738)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1976-1977; 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 739)
  - Agronomy Field Diary, 1979-1982; 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 740)
  - Field Diaries and Assorted Journals, Field Notebook, 1934-1935; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 741-742)
  - General Information, undated; 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 742)
- International Projects, Series 7
  - Colombia, 7.1
    - Application for Feasibility Study for a Watershed Stabilization Project: Rio Suarez Basin, undated; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 743)
    - Basin of the Suarez River: Plan for the Improvement of Hydraulic Resources, 1965; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 744)
    - Feasibility Report by Verle G. Kaiser, 1967-1973; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 745)
    - North Pacific Drainage Region, undated; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 746)
    - Report: Erosion Control Feasibility Study, Rio Suarez Basin Project, 1967; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 747)
    - Report on Atlantico Project Number Three, 1965; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 748)
    - Rio Suarez Feasibility Study: Basic Data, undated; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 749)
    - Soils of Ubate in the Province of Chiquinquira, 1965; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 750)
    - Suarez River Basin Feasibility Study, 1968; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 751)
  - Honduras, 7.2
    - Honduras Ambassador Meeting with Frederick T. Moore, 1970; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 752)
    - Project Memorandum, 1970; 10 items. (Box 12, Folder 753)
  - Iran, 7.3
    - Additional Crop Production Standards for Khuzestan, Adapted from Experiences at Mesa, Arizona, 1962; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 754)
    - Agricultural Development Bank of Iran, Final Report: Commercial Agriculture in Iran, 1975; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 755)
    - Agricultural Development in Iran, 1975; 6 items. (Box 12, Folder 756)
    - Agriculture in Iran and Columbia, 1967; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 757)
    - Agricultural and Rural Policy in Iran, 1972-1974; 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 758)
      - Production in a Traditional Village of Northern Khuzestan, undated; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 759)
    - Animal Husbandry, undated; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 760)
    - Barrage Chah Abbas Kabir Dam, 1966-1969; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 761)
    - Basic Legal Documents: Dez Irrigation Pilot Project, 1959-1961; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 762)
    - Basic Material, Khuzestan Agriculture, undated; 9 items. (Box 12, Folder 763)
    - Black and White Pictures of Khuzestan, undated; 62 items. (Box 12, Folder 764)
    - Cash Loans Extended to Rice Farmers and Fertilizer Distribution, 1963; 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 765)
    - Charts: Wheat Impact Program of MANR, undated; 3 items. (Box 12, Folder 766)
    - Climatology and Hydrology of Rice Cultivation, Khuzestan, undated; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 767)
    - Contract, 1975; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 768)
    - Contract Between Development Resources Corporation and Agricultural Development Bank of Iran, 1975; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 769)
    - Crop Management Recommendations: Dez Irrigation Project, 1975; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 770)
    - Crop Production in the Dez Pilot Area, undated; 3 items. (Box 13, Folder 771)
    - Data: Crop Yields, undated; 5 items. (Box 13, Folder 772)
    - Description of Trips to Iran, 1960's and summer of 1976; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 773)
    - Dez Project: A Revised Proposal, 1959; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 774)
      - 1959, 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 775)
      - 1959, 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 776)
      - Annual Report: Production Serviced, 1962-1963; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 777)
      - Annual Report: Production Serviced, 1974-1975; 8 items. (Box 13, Folder 778)
      - Annual Report: Production Serviced, 1974-1975; 8 items. (Box 13, Folder 779)
      - Crop Evaluation Studies, 1962-1963; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 780)
    - Draft of Work Plan, undated; 9 items. (Box 13, Folder 781)
      - General Information, 1959-1960; 11 items. (Box 13, Folder 782)
      - Job Description, 1960; 13 items. (Box 13, Folder 783)
      - Land Leveling: Estimated Cost and Procedures, 1963; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 784)
      - Monthly Report, 1963; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 785)
      - Personnel, 1960; 57 items. (Box 13, Folder 786)
      - Personnel, 1961; 33 items. (Box 13, Folder 787)
      - Spring and Summer Agricultural Program, 1963; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 788)
      - Spring and Summer Agricultural Program, 1963; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 789)
      - Status Report, 1963; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 790)
      - Village Production Service, 1963; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 791)
      - Work Plan, Revised, 1959-1961; 31 items. (Box 13, Folder 792)
      - Work Plan, Revised, 1962; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 793)
    - Dez Watershed Resource Management Plan: Government of Iran, 1974; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 794)
      - Stabilization Program, 1971; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 795)
    - "Enterprise in Iran: An Experiment in Economic Development," David E. Lilienthal, 1959; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 796)
    - Farm Management, 1976; 14 items. (Box 13, Folder 797)
      - Advisory Service, 1985; 3 items. (Box 13, Folder 798)
      - And Planning, 1976; 13 items. (Box 13, Folder 799)
      - In Iran, undated; 10 items. (Box 13, Folder 800)
    - Iran: Improving Farm Management, 1976; 7 items. (Box 13, Folder 801)
    - General Material, Dez Project, 1962-1975; 17 items. (Box 13, Folder 802)
      - Iran, undated; 9 items. (Box 13, Folder 803)
    - Iran Talk: "A Look at Trouble Iran Twenty Years Ago and Recently," Spokane, 1979; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 804)
      - Developments in the Khuzestan Region During the Past Twenty Years, 1978; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 805)
      - Peasant Life and Farming, undated; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 806)
      - "The Iran You Have Never Heard About--And What Went Wrong", 1980; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 807)
    - Karkheh: Notes from Reconnaissance Survey, 1975; 6 items. (Box 13, Folder 808)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1976; 31 items. (Box 13, Folder 809)